Pine Hills Fortnightly Club; Records apap031
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Pine Hills Fortnightly Club, INC. Records
1898-2003
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Pine Hills Fortnightly Club, INC.
apap031
2.5 cubic ft.
The Pine Hills Fortnightly Club was founded by Miss Mary M. Shaw in 1898 as a woman's literary and social club. According to the Club's earliest Constitution, "Its object shall be the study of history, literature and art and the literary and social entertainment of its members."
Access
Access to these records is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by the Albany County Planning Department on 24 February 1989. The items that were transferred were duplicates from the planning department; otherwise, photocopies were made by the archives.
Biographical History
The Pine Hills Fortnightly Club was founded by Miss Mary M. Shaw in 1898 as a woman's literary and social club. According to the Club's earliest Constitution, "Its object shall be the study of history, literature and art and the literary and social entertainment of its members."The Club was "federated" in 1900.Virtually from the Club's inception, meetings have been held on alternate Monday afternoons, from October 1st through April 30th.In the later Constitutions, the meeting schedule changed to "... the 2nd and 4th Mondays of each month from October to April inclusive, except the second meeting in December shall be omitted."Originally the membership was limited to twenty with dues of $ .50 annually. By 1901, they allowed the membership to reach fifty. Currently the annual dues are $25.00 and, during the last five years, active membership has averaged twenty.
An Executive Committee of the officers governs the Pine Hills Fortnightly Club: a president, two vice-presidents, recording secretary, corresponding secretary, treasurer, and the Program Committee Chairman. The other standing committees (auditing, membership, house, publicity, telephone, social, yearbook) have a chairman and the Club's president as anex officiomember. In later years, a librarian and historian were added, but there is no current record of those officers. Members are for the most part college-educated, well-read, active and engaged in various professions as is evident from the credentials cited in recommendation-for-membership letters and from the scope and content of the members' papers delivered at meetings.
According to the earliest Constitution, "At the end of each meeting not more than twenty minutes shall be devoted to business"; later the Constitution raised the time limit but did not exceed thirty minutes.The Club devoted the remaining meeting time, an estimated hour to an hour and a half, to the presentation of a member's paper followed by a discussion among the membership.
The literary focus of the Club's twice-a-month meetings is the presentation of papers. These scholarly papers center on a theme decided upon by the Program Committee as a year-long exploration of a particular topic. Using the available research tools a college-graduate would have at its disposal at the time, members focused on topics such as geographic locations, concepts relating to American historical development, works of fine art of particular periods or artists, and authors and their works. The collection exhibits well-researched papers addressing not only the topics but their possible social and historical ramifications; the presentation of these papers served as a form of continuing education for the membership.
The second part of the Pine Hills Fortnightly Club's constitutional objective is the "...social entertainment of its members." The Club's formal social functions consist of a Spring Luncheon held in May (the end to the Club's administrative year), and a Christmas party held during most years. The Spring Luncheon Programs have included the presentation of the theme for the following year's papers, the presentation of new officers, and the singing of the club song. The luncheon often features a guest speaker or a vocalist. The Christmas party, when held, was often the occasion for a choral reading by members or the singing of Christmas songs.
Scope and Contents
The Pine Hills Fortnightly Club Records, circa 1898-2001 (with gaps) include constitutions and by-laws, literary and social events programs and yearbooks, meeting minutes, attendance records, financial data, correspondence, letters of recommendation for candidates' membership, and newspaper clippings about members and other literary clubs that document the membership, history and the primary reasons for the Club's existence. Series 5 includes an account by Club members of their meeting with United Nations General Assembly President Vijaya Lakshmi Pandit of India.
The papers presented by Club members constitute half of the collection. The earliest paper in the collection is dated 1911. Many, but not all, papers listed with no date and no authors may be early presentations because these documents are handwritten with fountain pens. No papers exist in the collection from the 1920's or the 1960's.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series: Series 1: Constitutions and By-laws 1903-1991, Series 2: Programs, 1904-1913 and Yearbooks, 1913-2003, Series 3: Administrative Records, 1902-1995 Sub-Series 2: Correspondence, 1945-1997 Sub-Series 3: Committee Files, 1910-1988, Series 4: Financial Records 1913-2003, Series 5: Subject Files 1900-1997,Series 6: Papers Presented 1911-1984.Sub-Series 1: Secretary's Files, 1902-1995
Acquisition Information
The records were received from Eleanor Lattimer, President of the Pine Hills Fortnightly Club, Inc. The initial deposit of records was received by the University Libraries.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Women; Neighborhood and Community Associations; Albany, New York; Pine Hills Fortnightly Club, INC.
- Constitutions and By-laws, 1898-1991; 1; 0.1 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged Chronologically.
  Scope and Contents
  The collection contains the constitutions for 1898, 1903, and 1927-1991. The Constitution includes Articles, By-Laws, and Amendments. The Club's By-Laws specify the procedure by which new members are proposed. The earliest Pine Hills Fortnightly Club Constitution is handwritten in a notebook followed by the first recording of membership names dated 1900. Included in the constitutions are by-laws, articles, and amendments to the Constitutions. Constitutions often contain hand annotated revisions for incorporation into the next year's constitution.
  - Constitution and By-laws, 1988-1991 (Box 1 (1-Constitutions and By-laws), Folder 1)
- Programs and Yearbooks, 1900-2003; 2; 0.66 cubic ft.
  Arranged Alphabetically.
  Programmes are titled by the Club's annual themes. Programmes and Yearbooks have a copy of the Club Song, list the paper titles and presenter's name, the names of officers and committee members, and a listing of all active members, associate members, nonresident members, honorary members, and members "in memoriam." Beginning in 1921, a list of reference books, or a bibliography associated with the year's theme, became a standard inclusion. Program Committee files describe the formulation of the yearly themes and the provision of direction and guidance for the subject of a member's paper. The Committee assigns the schedule where members commit to delivering a paper at a scheduled meeting.
  - Annual Themes, 1900-1993 (Box 1 (2-Programs and Yearbooks), Folder 2)
  - Program Committee Suggestions for Annual Themes and Topics, 1964-1965; 1983-1995 (Box 1 (2-Programs and Yearbooks), Folder 3)
  - Programs, 1904-1913 (Box 1 (2-Programs and Yearbooks), Folder 4)
  - Yearbooks, 1913-1927 (Box 1 (2-Programs and Yearbooks), Folder 5)
  - Yearbooks, 1927-1941 (Box 1 (2-Programs and Yearbooks), Folder 6)
  - Yearbooks, 1941-1956 (Box 1 (2-Programs and Yearbooks), Folder 7)
  - Yearbooks, 1956-1976 (Box 1 (2-Programs and Yearbooks), Folder 8)
  - Yearbooks, 1976-2003 (Box 1 (2-Programs and Yearbooks), Folder 9)
  - Special Event Programs and Anniversary Papers, 1919-1982 (Box 1 (2-Programs and Yearbooks), Folder 10)
  - Spring Luncheon Programs, 1976-2003 (Box 1 (2-Programs and Yearbooks), Folder 11)
- Administrative Records, 1902-1999; 3; 0.87 cubic ft.
  Arranged.
  - Secretary's Files, 1902-1999; 3.1; 0.67 cubic ft.
    Arranged Alphabetically then Chronologically.
    The Recording Secretary's minutes of meetings have some gaps. The earliest recorded minutes in this collection are from 1902. The minutes are generally limited to one or one and a half pages. The minutes record Club activities at their meetings. The number of members present is listed, sometimes along with an attendance list. Next the secretary records the introduction of a topic, the title of the paper, and the presenter. The secretary also records briefly the actions of the business meeting following the presentations. Included also in the Sub-series are the minutes of the Executive Committees meetings for 1910-1923. Attendance records appear as part of Secretary's Minutes, except for a folder of separate attendance entries for 1903-1916 and 1941-1957.
    - Attendance Records, 1903-1916 (Box 1 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 12)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1902-1905 (Box 1 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 13)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1905-1909 (Box 1 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 14)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1909-1913 (Box 1 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 15)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1913-1917 (Box 1 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 16)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1917-1922 (Box 1 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 17)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1922-1931 (Box 1 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 18)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1951-1956 (Box 1 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 19)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1956-1961 (Box 1 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 20)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1961-1965 (Box 1 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 21)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1965-1967 (Box 1 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 22)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1967-1968 (Box 1 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 23)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1968-1969 (Box 1 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 24)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1969-1970 (Box 1 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 25)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1970-1971 (Box 1 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 26)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1971-1972 (Box 1 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 27)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1972-1973 (Box 1 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 28)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1973-1974 (Box 2 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 1)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1974-1976 (Box 2 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 2)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1980-1981 (Box 2 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 3)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1986-1987 (Box 2 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 4)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1987-1989 (Box 2 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 5)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1992-1995 (Box 2 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 6)
    - Secretary's Minutes, 1995-1999 (Box 2 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1945-1997; 3.2; 0.10 cubic ft.
    The Correspondence sub-series includes notes and correspondence regarding the disposition of the Club's archival records; informal and social correspondence; and letters regarding meeting sites; and correspondence with the printing company which printed yearbooks, and programs.
    - Archival Disposition of Records, 1988-1997 (Box 2 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1971-1999 (Box 2 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 9)
    - Printing Correspondence, 1945-1954 (Box 2 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 10)
  - Committee Files, 1910-1988; 3.3; 0.10 cubic ft.
    This sub-series includes records from the executive committee and the membership committee. Included in membership files are membership recommendations with the credentials of a proposed member (college[s] attended, professional development, posts held, awards won). Some recommendation letters also include the credentials of the proposed member's husband. See also Series 1: Programmes and Yearbooks for records of the Program Committee.
    - Duties of Committees, 1975 (Box 2 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 11)
    - Executive Committee Meetings and copy ofRobert's Rules of Order, 1910-1923 (Box 2 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 12)
    - Membership Recommendations, 1944-1988 (Box 2 (3-Administrative Records), Folder 13)
- Financial Records, 1913-2003; 4; 0.15 cubic ft.
  Bound ledgers record the expenses of the club's activities and printing fees. Dues records are kept in the ledgers, along with "fines" before the club ceased the fining system. This series also includes budget proposals for 1990-1993 and the Treasurer's Report of 1994.
  - Budget Ledgers, 1913-1922; 1935-1936 (Box 2 (4-Financial Records), Folder 14)
  - Budget Ledgers, 1928-1960 (Box 2 (4-Financial Records), Folder 15)
  - Budget Ledgers, 1963-1969 (Box 2 (4-Financial Records), Folder 16)
  - Budget Proposal, 1992-1993 (Box 2 (4-Financial Records), Folder 17)
- Subject Files, 1900-1996; 5; 0.20 cubic ft.
  Subject files include memorials, news clippings, plays presented, and press notices. There are memorials and tributes to some deceased members illustrating aspects of the social ties among the women, as well as news clippings about members and their families. Other news clippings illustrate the Club's relation to the community and the nature of long-lived literary clubs. News clippings are included in the folder that records the 1953 visit of twenty-three Club members to the United Nations to meet the first woman ever to be elected President of the General Assembly, Madam Vijaya Lakshmi Pandit, as well as a transcript of the interview they conducted with President Pandit.
  - Guest Day, Photographs, 2002 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Memorial for Member Ruth Birdseye (1904-1993) (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Memorial for Member Martha Decker (1892-1985),"Miss Decker," from Girls Academy, publication of Albany Academy Girls, 1993 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Memorial for Member Lillian A Johnson, 2003 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Memorial for Member Edith Owen Wallace (1896-1972), held February 19, 1972 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - News Clipping, "Literary clubs live on--but for how long?" Albany, NY Times Union, February 24, 1980 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - News Clipping, "Church council names director" on Gladys and Jim Snedeker, Albany, NY Times Union, June 12, 1986 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - News Clipping, "Former Librarian's Portrait is Unveiled," on Alice Murphy, 1972 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - News Clipping, "90 Years is a very long time" on 90th anniversary of Thursday Morning Club, Troy, NY The Sunday Record, May 6, 1994 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Plays Presented, 1960s, undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Press Notices, 1937-1967; Undated (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Reading of First Meeting, 1997 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Visit to United Nations, Interview with General Assembly President Vijaya Lakshmi Pandit, 1953 (Box 2 (5-Subject Files), Folder 30)
- Papers Presented, 1911-2003; 6; 0.78 cubic ft.
  The author's name, the title of the paper, the date of presentation, and notation of any illustrations that may accompany a paper are included for each paper. Dates were identified from the actual paper, from the listing in Programmes and Yearbooks, or from secretary's minutes. A number of papers are titled but do not identify author or date presented.
  - "Empire State: Social Life and Customs, 1911 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 31)
  - "New England Poetry," by Frances V. Hubbard, 1933 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 32)
  - "Novel: The Scottish Queen," no author, 1933 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 33)
  - "Don Quixote and Cervantes," no author, 1935 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 34)
  - "The Lady of Godey's," no author, 1939 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 35)
  - "The Women of South America," no author, 1941 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 36)
  - "Handicaps and Triumphs of the Moslem Woman," by June Bowen, 1954 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 37)
  - "Passions of the Mind (Freud) by Irving Stone," by Mrs. Taylor, 1972 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 38)
  - "Ellen Browning Scripps," by Mrs. Taylor, 1975 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 39)
  - "Folk Art," by Mrs. Taylor, 1976 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 40)
  - "All of Time Is Still One History: Guy Davenport," by Mrs. Taylor, 1979 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 41)
  - "Emily Carr: Artist of the Canadian West Coast," by Georgiana Taylor, 1981 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 42)
  - "Roger Fry/ Duncan Grant," by Mrs. Taylor, 1984 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 43)
  - "Bertrand Russell," by Mabel E. Jackman, 1986 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 44)
  - "Sinclair Lewis: Gopher Prairie to Nobel Prize," by Elizabeth Slagle, 1986 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 45)
  - "The French Canadians: The Northern Flood," by Winifred Gibson, 1986 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 46)
  - "The Political Connection," by Mrs. Taylor, 1986 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 47)
  - "Eastern European Immigrants to Albany: Poles, Russians, Ukrainian, Armenians," by Charity M. Roth, 1987 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 48)
  - "The New Immigration: Hispanics and the Pacific Rim," by Mabel E. Jackman, 1987 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 49)
  - "The Spanish Main," by Gladys Snedeker, 1988 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 50)
  - "The Massachusetts Delegation to the Constitutional Convention of 1787," by Charity Roth, 1988 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 51)
  - "The Delegates from New Jersey," by Rhoda Castor, 1988 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 52)
  - "The Delegates from Pennsylvania," by Mrs. Robert Clarke, 1988 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 53)
  - "The Delegates from Delaware and Maryland," by Irene Walker, 1988 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 54)
  - "The Men Who Made the Constitution: A Bicentennial Portfolio," by Georgiana Taylor, 1988 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 55)
  - "The Delegates from Virginia," by Mrs. Taylor, 1988 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 56)
  - "The Finished Work," by Ruth A. Birdseye, 1988 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 57)
  - "Thrills and Chills: Gothic, 1988 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 58)
  - "Novel Approaches: Discovering the Formula, Murder They Wrote," by Marion Motisher, 1989 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 59)
  - "Entertaining Angels Unaware, Ghost Stories, 1989 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 60)
  - "Satire: Lord, What Fools These Mortals Be," by Lois V.Williams, 1989 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 61)
  - "Check Your Valuables: Picaresque Fiction," by Ethel Long Severinghaus, 1989 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 62)
  - "From The Bookish Brothers Grimm, A Flood of Fantasy, (Kathleen Burke, Smithsonian, May 1986): Once Upon a Time," by Betty Slagle, 1989 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 63)
  - "Listen, my children," by Marion E. Mayfield, 1989 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 64)
  - "A Tale of Two Cities," by Mary G. Coggin, 1989 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 65)
  - "Animal Stories," by Doris Welsh, 1989 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 66)
  - "Constantinople," by Evelyn Jenkins, 1989 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 67)
  - "Minoan Crete," by Lillian Johnson, 1989 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 68)
  - "Xi'an: Ancient Capital of China," by Winifred Gibson, 1989 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 69)
  - "The Suburban Woman as Viewed by Betty Friedan," by Doris Welsh, 1989 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 70)
  - "CLUNY: To the Glory of God," by Barbara Rau, 1990 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 71)
  - "Regarding Venice," by Mary Ellen Stewart, 1990 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 72)
  - "Paris in the Seventeenth Century: King Louis XIV and the Population," by Rhoda Castor, 1990 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 73)
  - "Peter the Great: The Man and his Impact on Russia," (Pictures and Notes on Peter the Great) by Charity Roth, 1990 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 74)
  - "London: The Victorian Period," (3 illus.) by Georgiana Taylor, 1990 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 75)
  - "The Arts of Poland," by Ethel Severinghaus, 1990 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 76)
  - "(Alva Nurierz) Cabeza de Vaga," by Evelyn Jenkins, 1991 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 77)
  - "The Madwoman of Chaillot by Jean Giraudoux," (play reading) Cast members: Alice Murphy, Rhoda Castor, Georgiana Taylor, Doris Welsh, Hilda Olivo, Betty Slagle, Marion Mothisher, Lillian Johnson, Frances Allee, 1991 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 78)
  - "The City of Dresden," by Mrs. Lattimer, 1991 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 79)
  - "The Gypsies," by Mrs. Welsh, 1991 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 80)
  - "Christopher Columbus," by Charity Roth, 1991 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 81)
  - "Western Star by Stephen Vincent Benet" (choral reading), 1991 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 82)
  - "Henry Hudson: Magnificent Failure/Samuel de Champlain: Father of New France," by Georgiana Taylor (14 illus.), 1992 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 83)
  - "Edith Wharton: The Many Faceted Woman," by Ethel Severinghaus, 1992 (Box 2 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 84)
  - "Charlotte Bronte," by Doris Welsh, 1992 (Box 3 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 1)
  - "Leonardo da Vinci's The Last Supper," by Betty Slagle. "The Pyramids," by Mrs. Melius, 1993 (Box 3 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 2)
  - "Robert Oppenheimer, Father of the Atom Bomb." Also: "Peggy Church's Dream" from Peggy Pond Church's, The House at Otowi Bridge, by Charity Roth, 1993 (Box 3 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 3)
  - "The Masterpiece: Carmen, and How it Came to Be," by Eleanor Clarke, 1993 (Box 3 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 4)
  - "The Child: John Dewey to Marion Edelman," by Evelyn Jenkins, 1993 (Box 3 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 5)
  - "The State Capitol and Its Environs," by Georgiana Taylor, 1994 (Box 3 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 6)
  - "Washington Irving and His Friends," by Charity M. Roth, 1994 (Box 3 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 7)
  - "Leonard Bernstein: From the Classics to West Side Story," by Mrs. Rau, 1994 (Box 3 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 8)
  - "Food in History," by Elizabeth Slagle, 1994 (Box 3 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 9)
  - "Losing Ground," by Charity M. Roth, 1994 (Box 3 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 10)
  - "Festival Foods from Around the World," by Gladys Snedeker, 1994 (Box 3 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 11)
  - "Food and Trade: National Monopolies on Various Foodstuffs And the Economic Results," by Vera Scadura, 1994 (Box 3 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 12)
  - "Food As Destiny: The Old World Meets the New at the Table," by Eleanor Lattimer, 1995 (Box 3 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 13)
  - "Food Taboos in Various Cultures," by Charity M. Roth, 1995 (Box 3 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 14)
  - "Eleanor Roosevelt and the Great Depression," by Charity M. Roth, 1995 (Box 3 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 15)
  - "Evolution in the Telephone Industry," by Charity M. Roth, 1995 (Box 3 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 16)
  - "From the Piggy Bank to the ATM," by Vera Scadura, 1996 (Box 3 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 17)
  - "Barbara McClintock, Rosalyn Sussman Yalow, Rachel Carson," by Evelyn Jenkins, 1996 (Box 3 (6-Papers Presented), Folder 18)